Edward Grant papers, 1950-2001 C184
Indiana University Archives
- Student work, 1950-1959
  - (University of Wisconsin) (Box 10)
    - Seminar 205, Fall 1954 (Box 11)
    - Graduate notes, 1951-1957; 1954-1957; (6 folders) (Box 11)
    - Medieval Culture, 1954-1957; (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - 120b Medieval science, 1954-1957 (Box 11)
    - Graduate notes: Wisconsin, Columbia Univ., 1954-1957 (Box 11)
    - Integrated Liberal studies, Spring 1957 (Box 11)
    - History of Italy, Spring 1957 (Box 11)
    - Notes/Research, undated; (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - Graduate notes--Harvard University, Spring 1959; (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - Dissertation (Box 11)
      - (Title page-Chapter V), 1957 (Box 11)
      - (Chapter VI), 1957 (Box 11)
      - (Chapter VII-end), 1957 (Box 11)
    - Doctoral Thesis (same as above), 1957 (Box 11)
- Research, 1955-1992
  Scope and Contents
  See also box 24, which is the last box and contains index cards full of research notes.
  - Miscellaneous
    - University of Utrecht--Fulbright Scholarship, 1955 (Box 11)
    - Research compiled from European manuscripts (Box 11)
      - 1953-1954 (Box 11)
      - 1956 (Box 11)
      - undated (Box 11)
    - Research notes taken in Europe, undated; (2 folders) (Box 11)
    - Research notes taken in Europe, undated; (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - Miscellaneous microfilmed manuscripts, undated (Box 12)
    - Manuscripts by subject, undated; (2 folders) (Box 12)
    - Manuscripts by library, undated (Box 12)
    - Microfilm lists, undated (Box 12)
  - Grant Proposals, 1961-1992
    - American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS), 3 Feb 1961 (Box 12)
    - ACLS award, 1974 (Box 12)
    - Guggenheim Foundation (Box 12)
      - 1965 (Box 12)
      - 1974 (Box 12)
    - Indiana University's Research Incentive Program, 1979-1982 (Box 12)
    - NEH (National Endowment for Humanities) (Box 12)
      - Summer seminar (Box 12)
        - 1975 (Box 12)
        - 1978 (Box 12)
        - 1980, (2 folders) (Box 12)
      - Translation proposal, 1983 (Box 12)
      - Proposal: The Medieval Cosmos, 1984 (Box 12)
      - Grant, 1984 (Box 12)
    - NSF (National Science Foundation) (Box 12)
      - Grants, 1959-1971 (Box 12)
      - Grant G8674, 1959-1960 (Box 12)
      - Grant proposals, 1961-1963 (Box 12)
      - 6S-66, May 1963 (Box 12)
      - Grants: Purchase requisitions, 1963-1965 (Box 12)
      - Grant GS-1074, 1966-1968 (Box 12)
      - Publication subsidy, 1967 (Box 12)
      - Grant GS-1961, 1970-1972 (Box 12)
      - Grants: proposals, 1971-1974 (Box 12)
      - Proposals, 1979-1982 (Box 12)
      - Proposal: The Medieval World View, 1979-1982 (Box 12)
      - NSF, cont. Grant: Scientific inertia, 1980-1982 (Box 13)
      - Proposals, 1982-1989 (Box 13)
      - Proposal: The Medieval Cosmos, 1984-1989 (Box 13)
      - NSF-NEH Proposal for Medieval Cosmos, 1989 (Box 13)
      - Proposal: Medieval Cosmos, 1990 (Box 13)
      - Application, 1990 (Box 13)
      - Dir-901 1540, 1991-1992 (Box 13)
    - Newberry Library, 1980 (Box 13)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1974 (Box 13)
  - Research for articles, 1962-1976
    - Aristotle's Shiphaulers, 1962 (Box 13)
    - Mathematical uncertainty in middle ages, undated (Box 13)
    - Part I of Oresme's Algorismus Proportionum, 1965 (Box 13)
    - Place and space in medieval physical thought, 1976; (2 folders) (Box 13)
  - Research for Oresme: De Proportionibus...,(pub. 1966), undated
    - Research/notes, undated (Box 13)
    - Notes, undated; (4 folders) (Box 13)
    - Microfilmed manuscripts, undated; (2 folders) (Box 13)
  - Research for Oresme: Kinematics of Circular Motion, (pub. 1971), undated
    - Arsenal 522, undated (Box 13)
    - Florence ASHB 210, undated (Box 13)
    - Lawrence de Fundis, undated (Box 13)
    - Utrecht 725, undated (Box 13)
    - Vatican Lat 4082, Pepys 2329, undated; (2 folders) (Box 13)
    - Notes and comments, undated (Box 13)
    - BN 7281, undated (Box 13)
    - Cicero on great year, undated (Box 13)
    - Johannes de Mures, undated (Box 13)
    - Theodosius of Tripoli, undated (Box 13)
    - Transparencies, undated (Box 13)
  - Research for A Source Book, (pub. 1974), undated
    - Research for book, early materials, undated; (2 folders) (Box 13)
  - Research for Much Ado About Nothing, (pub. 1981), undated
    - Manuscripts and enlargements, undated; (3 folders) (Box 13)
    - Xeroxes relevant to chapter 8, undated; (2 folders) (Box 14)
    - Al-Farabi & Peter of Alvernia: On vacuum, undated (Box 14)
    - Algazali: on void, undated (Box 14)
    - Amicus: on place, undated (Box 14)
    - Aristotle: on void, undated (Box 14)
    - Avicenna: on void, undated (Box 14)
    - Roger Bacon: on void, undated (Box 14)
    - Beauvais, Vincent of: on place, undated (Box 14)
    - Blasius of Parma: (Box 14)
      - on vacuum, undated (Box 14)
      - on void, undated (Box 14)
    - Nicolas Bonetas: on vacuum, undated (Box 14)
    - Bruno: infinite space, undated (Box 14)
    - Buridan: (Box 14)
      - on place, undated (Box 14)
      - on vacuum, undated (Box 14)
    - Walter Burley: on place, undated (Box 14)
    - Johannes Canonicus: on place, undated (Box 14)
    - Cardano, undated (Box 14)
    - Cardano, cont., equality of man, undated (Box 14)
    - Cleomedes: on vacuum, undated (Box 14)
    - Melchior Cornaeus, undated (Box 14)
    - Luis Coronel: on place, undated (Box 14)
    - Bartholomeo D'Amici: (Box 14)
      - on place, undated (Box 14)
      - on vacuum, undated (Box 14)
    - St. John of Damascus: on place, undated (Box 14)
    - Descartes on space, undated (Box 14)
    - "Fluid" void, undated (Box 14)
    - Gaetanus de Thienis, undated (Box 14)
    - Giovanni di Ascoli Graziadei, undated (Box 14)
    - Giovanni da Fontana, undated (Box 14)
    - PS Grosseteste: on place, undated (Box 14)
    - Henry of Ghent: on place, undated (Box 14)
    - Hero of Alexandria: on void, undated (Box 14)
    - Infinite space, Concept of, undated (Box 14)
    - Interstitial vacuum, undated (Box 14)
    - The Italian Natural Philosophers, undated; (2 folders) (Box 14)
    - J.B. de la Grange: on void, undated (Box 14)
    - Jesuits, undated (Box 14)
    - John of Jandun: on vacuum, undated (Box 14)
    - John of St. Thomas, undated (Box 14)
    - Jordanus de Nemorarius, undated (Box 14)
    - Albertus Magnus: on place, undated (Box 14)
    - Emanuel Maignan, undated; (2 folders) (Box 14)
    - Mathematical infinite, On the, undated (Box 14)
    - Moerbeke, William of, undated (Box 14)
    - Nature abhors a vacuum, undated (Box 14)
    - Nicholas of Autrecourt, undated (Box 14)
    - Ockham: on void, undated (Box 14)
    - Oresme: on void, undated (Box 14)
    - Francesco Patrizi, undated; (2 folders) (Box 15)
    - Paul of Venice, undated; (2 folders) (Box 15)
    - Peter of Abano, undated (Box 15)
    - Petrus of Aureoli: on place, undated (Box 15)
    - John Philoponus: on void, undated (Box 15)
    - S. Pines: Islamischen Atomenlehre, undated (Box 15)
    - Place, misc. discussions, undated (Box 15)
    - Place and ubi, undated (Box 15)
    - Place, void, space, undated; (6 folders) (Box 15)
    - Giorgio Polacco, undated (Box 15)
    - Principle of intertia, undated (Box 15)
    - Regiomantus, undated (Box 15)
    - Aegidius Romanus: on place, undated (Box 15)
    - Rotation of Earth, undated (Box 15)
    - Duns Scotus: on place, undated (Box 15)
    - Separate void, undated (Box 15)
    - Siger of Brabant, undated (Box 15)
    - Simplicius: on vacuum, undated (Box 15)
    - Domingo Soto: (Box 15)
      - on place, undated (Box 15)
      - on vacuum, undated (Box 15)
    - Spinoza: on space, undated (Box 15)
    - Franciscus Toletus: on place, undated (Box 15)
    - Vacuum, Definitions of, undated (Box 15)
    - Void, General views on, undated (Box 15)
    - On void, space, undated (Box 15)
    - Void, space, action at a distance, undated (Box 15)
    - Void as discussed in hermetic literature, undated (Box 15)
    - Void, Experiments in middle ages, undated (Box 15)
    - Void space, undated (Box 15)
  - Research for Jordanus de Nemore (unpublished), undated
    - Jordanus: Biblioteque Nationale BN16644, undated; (2 folders) (Box 15)
    - Biblioteque Nationale 14737, undated; (2 folders) (Box 15)
    - Cambridge Univ. Library 1876, undated (Box 15)
    - Milano manuscript C-241INF, undated; (2 folders) (Box 15)
    - Pepys 2329, undated; (2 folders) (Box 16)
    - Photocopy of Vatican Manuscript, undated; (2 folders) (Box 16)
    - Vatican manuscript 2120, undated; (3 folders) (Box 16)
    - Vat. Lat. 4455, undated; (2 folders) (Box 16)
    - Grant's notes, undated; (2 folders) (Box 16)
- Publications, 1961-2001
  - Correspondence, 1963-1988
    - Cambridge University Press (Box 16)
      - 1972-1980 (Box 16)
      - 1981-1985 (Box 16)
    - John Wiley Press, 1965-1972; (2 folders) (Box 16)
    - University of Wisconsin Press (Box 16)
      - Halftones for 2 published books, 1966; 1971 (Box 16)
      - Oresme volumes, undated (Box 16)
    - Correspondence regarding Oresme De Proportionibus..., 1963-1966; 1988 (Box 16)
    - Correspondence for Source Book, 1968-1974 (Box 16)
    - Correspondence for Much Ado, 1978-1981 (Box 16)
  - Articles, 1960-1997
    The arrangement of this subseries closely follows the list of articles in Dr. Grant's Curriculum Vitae.
    - "Nicole Oresme and his De Proportionibus Proportionum."Isis 51, no. 165: 293-314., (1960) (Box 16)
    - "Nicole Oresme and the Commensurability or Incommensurability of Celestial Motions." Archive for History of Exact Sciences 1: 420-458., (1961) (Box 16)
    - "Late Medieval Thought, Copernicus, and the Scientific Revolution." Journal of the History of Ideas 23: 197-220., (1962) (Box 16)
    - "Hypotheses in Late Medieval and Early Modern Science." Daedalus Summer: 599-616., (1962) (Box 16)
    - "Jean Buridan: A 14th Century Cartesian." Archives Internationales d'Histoire des Sciences 16, no. 64: 251-255., (1963) (Box 16)
    - "Aristotle's Shiphaulers' and Medieval Criticisms of His Law of Motion." Dixième Congrès International d'Histoire des Sciences 1: 587-590., (1964) (Box 16)
    - "Aristotle's Restriction on His Law of Motion: Its Fate in the Middle Ages." In L'Aventure de la Science. Mèlanges Alexandre Koyré (Histoire de la Pensée, vol. 12). Paris: Hermann,: 173-197., 1964 (Box 16)
    - "Motion in the Void and the Principle of Inertia in the Middle Ages." Isis 55, no. 181: 265-292., (1964) (Box 16)
    - "Bradwardine and Galileo: Equality of Velocities in the Void." Archive for History of Exact Sciences 2, no. 4: 344-364., (1965) (Box 16)
    - "Part I of Nicole Oresme's Algorismus Proportionum." Isis 56, part 3, no. 185: 327-341., (1965) (Box 16)
    - "Aristotle, Philoponus, Avempace, and Galileo's Pisan Dynamics." Centaurus 11, no. 2: 79-95., (1965) (Box 16)
    - "Oresme, Nicholas." The Encyclopedia of Philosophy New York/London,, vol. 5, 547, c. 1-549, c. 1., 1967 (Box 16)
    - "Science in the Middle Ages." The New Catholic Encyclopedia,, vol. 12, 1200, c. 1-1209, c. 1., 1967 (Box 16)
    - "On the Origin of the Medieval Version of Equality of Fall for Unequal Bodies in the Void: A Critique of Duhem's Explanation." Actes du XI Congrès International d'Histoire des Sciences Warsaw/Cracow,, vol. 3, 19-23., 1967 (Box 16)
    - "Medieval and 17th Century Conceptions of an Infinite Void Space Beyond the Cosmos. " Isis 60, part 1, no. 201: 39-60., (1969) (Box 16)
    - "Blasius of Parma." Dictionary of Scientific Biography New York: Charles Scribner's Sons,, vol. 2, 192, c.2-195, c.2., 1970 (Box 16)
    - "The Arguments of Nicholas of Autrecourt for the Existence of Interparticulate Vacua." Actes du XII Congrès International d'Histoire des Sciences Paris: Albert Blanchard, ,tome IIIA, 65-68., 1971 (Box 16)
    - Commentary on Marshall Clagett "Archimedes in the Late Middle Ages." In Duane H.D. Roller (ed.), Perspectives in the History of Science and Technology. Norman, Oklahoma: University of Oklahoma Press,, 260-263., 1971 (Box 16)
    - "Henricus Aristippus, William of Moerbeke and Two Alleged Mediaeval Translations of Hero's Pneumatica." Speculum 46, no. 4: 656-669., (1971) (Box 16)
    - Materials relating to translation of Philo of Byzantium, 1971-1972 (Box 16)
    - Essay Review of Marshall Clagett Nicole Oresme and the Medieval Geometry of Qualities and Motions. A Treatise on the Uniformity and Difformity of Intensities known as "Tractatus de configurationibus qualitatum et motuum." Reviewed in Studies in History and Philosophy of Science 3: 167-182., (1972) (Box 16)
    - "Jordanus de Nemore", 1973 (Box 16)
    - "Medieval Explanations and Interpretations of the Dictum that 'Nature Abhors a Vacuum'." Traditio 29: 327-355., (1973) (Box 16)
    - "In Memoriam: Anneliese Maier (1905-1971)." Archives Internationales d'Histoire des Sciences 24, no. 94: 143-144., (June, 1974) (Box 16)
    - "Peter Peregrinus." Dictionary of Scientific Biography. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons,, vol. 10, 532-540., 1974 (Box 16)
    - "Pomponius Mela." Dictionary of Scientific Biography. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons,, vol. 11, 74-76., 1975 (Box 16)
    - "Place and Space in Medieval Physical Thought." In Motion and Time, Space and Matter: Interrelations in the History of Philosophy and Science. Edited by Peter K. Machamer and Robert G. Turnbull. Columbus, Ohio: Ohio State University Press, 137-167., 1976 (Box 16)
    - "The Concept of Ubi in Medieval and Renaissance Discussions of Place." In Science, Medicine, and the University: 1200-1550. Essays in Honor of Pearl Kibre Manuscripta 20, Part I, 71-80., (July, 1976) (Box 16)
    - "Aristotelianism and the Longevity of the Medieval World View." In History of Science, xvi (1978): 93-106. (Box 16)
    - "Scientific Thought in Fourteenth-Century Paris: Jean Buridan and Nicole Oresme." In Machaut's World: Science and Art in the Fourteenth Century. Edited by Madeleine Pelner Cosman and Bruce Chandler. Annals of the New York Academy of Science v. 314. New York: The New York Academy of Sciences,, 105-124., 1978 (Box 16)
    - "The Principle of Impenetrability of Bodies in the History of Concepts of Space from the Middle Ages to the Seventeenth Century." Isis 69, no. 249: 551-571., (1978) (Box 16)
    - Dictionary of the Middles Ages articles, 1978-1979 (Box 16)
    - "The Condemnation of 1277, God's Absolute Power, and Physical Thought in the Late Middle Ages." Viator 10,: 211-244., (1979) (Box 16)
    - Articles in Press, 1980-1983 (Box 16)
    - "History and Philosophy of Science", 1981 (Box 16)
    - "The Medieval Doctrine of Place: Some Fundamental Problems and Solutions. In Studi sul XIV secolo in memoria di Anneliese Maier. Edited by A. Maierù and A. Paravicini Bagliani (Storie e Letteratura, 151). Rome: Edizioni di Storia e Letteratura,, 57-79., 1981 (Box 16)
    - "Celestial Matter: A Medieval and Galilean Cosmological Problem." The Journal of Medieval and Renaissance Studies 13, no. 2: 157-186., (fall, 1983) (Box 16)
    - "Were there Significant Differences Between Medieval and Early Modern Scholastic Natural Philosophy? The Case for Cosmology." Nous 18, no. 1: 5-14., (March, 1984) (Box 17)
    - "Science and the Medieval University." In James M. Kittelson and Pamela J. Transue, eds. Rebirth, Reform and Resilience: Universities in Transition 1300-1700. Columbus: Ohio State University Press, 68-102., 1984 (Box 17)
    - "Celestial Perfection from the Middle Ages to the Late Seventeenth Century." In Margaret J. Osler and Paul Lawrence Farber, eds., Religion, Science and Worldview. Essays in Honor of Richard S. Westfall. Cambridge, Eng.: Cambridge University Press, 137-162., 1985 (Box 17)
    - "Issues in Natural Philosophy at Paris in the Late Thirteenth Century." Medievalia et Humanistica New Series, Number 13 (Paul Maurice Clogan, ed.),, 75-94., 1985 (Box 17)
    - "A New Look at Medieval Cosmology, 1200-1687." Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society 129, no. 4: 417-432., (Dec., 1985) (Box 17)
    - "Dynamik." Article in Lexikon des Mittelalters 3, cols. 1493-1496. (Box 17)
    - "Science and Theology in the Middle Ages." In David C. Lindberg and Ronald L. Numbers, eds., God and Nature, Historical Essays on the Encounter between Christianity and Science. Berkeley/Los Angeles: University of California Press, 49-75., 1986 (Box 17)
    - "Eloge: Edward Rosen", 1986 (Box 17)
    - "Anomalies in Medieval Science", 1987 (Box 17)
    - "Medieval and Renaissance Scholastic Conceptions of the Influence of the Celestial Region on the Terrestrial." The Journal of Medieval and Renaissance Studies 17, no. 1: 1-23., (Spring, 1987) (Box 17)
    - "Eccentrics and Epicycles in Medieval Cosmology." In Edward Grant and John E. Murdoch, eds., Mathematics and its Applications to Science and Natural Philosophy in the Middle Ages: Essays in Honor of Marshall Clagett. Cambridge, Eng.: Cambridge University Press,, 189-214., 1987 (Box 17)
    - "Celestial Orbs in the Latin Middle Ages." Isis 78, no. 292: 153-173., (June, 1987) (Box 17)
    - "Ways to Interpret the Terms 'Aristotelian' and 'Aristotelianism' in Medieval and Renaissance Natural Philosophy." History of Science 25,: 335-358., (1987) (Box 17)
    - Lynn White Memoir, 1987-1988; (2 folders) (Box 17)
    - "Medieval Departures from Aristotelian Natural Philosophy." In Studies in Medieval Natural Philosophy ed. Stefano Caroti. Biblioteca di Nuncius, Studi e Testi. Firenze: Leo S. Olschki,, 237-256., 1989 (Box 17)
    - "The Parisian School of Science in the Fourteenth Century." with John E. Murdoch. In Guttorm Flasted, ed. Contemporary Philosophy, A New Survey, vol. 6: Philosophy of Science in the Middle Ages. Co-editor Raymond Klibansky. Dodrect/Boston/London: Kluwer Academic Publishers, 481-493., 1990 (Box 17)
    - "Celestial Incorruptibility in Medieval Cosmology 1200-1687." In Sabetai Unguru, ed., Physics, Cosmology and Astronomy, 1300-1700. The Netherlands: Kluwer Academic Publishers, 101-127., 1991 (Box 17)
    - "The Unusual Structure and Organization of Albert of Saxony's Questions on Decoelo." In Joël Biard, ed. Itinéraires d'Albert de Saxe Paris-Vienne au XIV Siècle. Paris: Libraires Philosophique J. Vrin,, 205-217., 1991 (Box 17)
    - "Science in the Late Fifteenth Century." Article in Silvio A. Bedini, ed., The Christopher Columbus Encyclopedia 2 vols. New York: Simon Schuster,, vol. 2, 601-604., 1992 (Box 17)
    - Obituary for Vic Thoren, 1991-1992 (Box 17)
    - "Jean Buridan and Nicole Oresme on Natural Knowledge." Vivarium 3, no. 1: 84-105., (1993) (Box 17)
    - "A Comparison of Oresme's French and Latin Commentaries" For Murdoch Festschrift, 1992-1996 (Box 17)
    - Revised Bibliographic Essay for French Physical Science in Middle Ages, 1992 (Box 17)
    - "Medieval Cosmology." In Norris S. Hetherington, ed., Cosmology: Historical, Literary, Philosophical, Religious, and Scientific Perspectives. New York: Garland Publishing, Inc., 181-199., 1993 (Box 17)
    - "La Nature a horreur du vide." A contribution to "Les Grandes Expérience de la Physique Blaise Pascal: Comment a-t-il démontré l'existence de la pression atmosphérique?" In Les Cahiers de Science & Vie hors série, No. 27, 26-33., (Juin 1995) (Box 17)
    - "Why you should believe that Modern Science began in the Middle Ages", 1995 (Box 17)
    - "Astronomy, Cosmology, and Cosmography." In F. A. C. Mantello and A. G. Rigg (eds.), Medieval Latin: An Introduction and Bibliographical Guide. Washington, D. C.: The Catholic University of America Press, 363-368., 1996 (Box 17)
    - "Aristotelianism in the Early 12th Cent.", 1996 (Box 17)
    - "When did Modern Science Begin?" The American Scholar,: 105-113., Winter 1997 (Box 17)
    - "Celestial Motions in the Late Middle Ages." Early Science and Medicine 2, no. 2, Special Issue: "Medieval Cosmologies," edited by J. M. M. H. Thijssen, 129-148., (June 1997) (Box 17)
    - "Nicole Oresme, Aristotle's On the Heavens, and the Court of Charles V." In Texts and Contexts in Ancient and Medieval Science: Studies on the Occasion of John E. Murdoch's Seventieth Birthday, edited by Edith Sylla and Michael McVaugh. Leiden: Brill, 187-207., 1997 (Box 17)
    - "The Medieval Cosmos: Its Structure and Operation." Journal for the History of Astronomy 28,: 147-167., (1997) (Box 17)
    - "Medieval Concepts of Force, Resistance, and Velocity.", undated (Box 17)
    - "Astronomies and Cultures.", undated (Box 17)
  - Reviews, 1961-1998
    All of the following reviews were written by Dr. Grant
    - Wallace, William A. Review of The Scientific Methodology of Theodoric of Freiberg: A Case Study of the Relationship between Science and Philosophy. Reviewed in Speculum 36,: 188-194., (Jan. 1961) (Box 17)
    - Gundell. Review of Weltbild und Astrologie in den Griechischen Zauberpapyri, 1962 (Box 17)
    - Crombie, A. C., ed. Review of Scientific Change. Reviewed in American Biology Teacher 26, no. 3: 216-218., (March 1964) (Box 17)
    - Lewis, C. S. Review of The Discarded Image: An Introduction to Medieval and Renaissance Literature. Reviewed in Isis 56, part 1, no. 183: 99-100., (1965) (Box 17)
    - Beaujouan, Guy. Review of Manuscrits Scientifiques Medievaux de L'Universite de Salamanque et de Ses "Colegios Mayores." Reviewed in Isis 56, part 2, no. 184: 239-240., (1965) (Box 17)
    - St. Thomas Aquinas. Review of Commentary on Aristotle's Physics. Translated by Richard J. Blackwell, Richard J. Spath, and W. Edmund Thirlkel. Reviewed in Isis 56, part 4, no. 186: 474-475., (1965) (Box 17)
    - Baron, Roger, ed. Review of Hugonis de Sancto Victore Opera Propaedeutica: Practica Geometriae, de Grammatica, Epitome Dindimi in Philosophiam. Reviewed in Isis 59:342-343., (1968) (Box 17)
    - Drake. Review of Two News Sciences by Galileo., 1968-1972 (Box 17)
    - Drake, Stillman and I. E. Drabkin. Review of Mechanics in Sixteenth-Century Italy. Selections from Tartaglia, Benedetti, Guido Ubaldo, & Galileo. Reviewed in Renaissance Quarterly 24, no. 3:381-383., (Autumn 1971) (Box 17)
    - Talbot, H. Review of Medicine in Medieval England. Reviewed in Science 171, no. 3966: 55., (1971) (Box 17)
    - Pedersen, Olaf and Mogens Pihl. Review of Early Physics and Astronomy. Reviewed in Journal for the History of Astronomy 7,: 201-204., (1976) (Box 17)
    - Review of Lexikon des Mittelalters. Reviewed in Journal of the History of Medicine and Allied Sciences 34,: 382-383., (July 1979) (Box 17)
    - Murray, Alexander. Review of Reason and Society in the Middle Ages. Reviewed in Isis 71, no. 257: 340-341., (June 1980) (Box 17)
    - Gillispie, Charles C., ed. Review of The Dictionary of Scientific Biography. Reviewed in "The DSB: A Review Symposium" by Donald Fleming, Joseph Needham, Edward Grant, and Jacques Roger in Isis 71,: 633-652., (1980) (Box 17)
    - Hilfstein, Erna, Czartoryski, Pawel, and Frank D. Grande. Review of Science and History: Studies in Honor of Edward Rosen. Reviewed in Renaissance Quarterly 34, no. 2: 213-215., (Summer 1981) (Box 17)
    - Wallace, William A. Review of Prelude to Galileo: Essays on Medieval and Sixteenth-Century Sources of Galileo's Thought. Reviewed in Science 214, no. 4516: 55-56., (October 1981) (Box 17)
    - White, Lynn. Review of Medieval Religion and Technology: Collected Essays. Reviewed in Archives Internationale d'Histoire des Sciences 31, no. 106: 215-217., (1981) (Box 17)
    - Poulle, Emmanuel. Review of Les Sources Astronomiques (Textes, Tables, Instruments). Reviewed in Isis 73, no. 269:596-597., (1982) (Box 17)
    - Maier, Anneliese. Review of On the Threshold of Exact Science: Selected Writings of Anneliese Maier on Late Medieval Natural Philosophy. Reviewed in Isis 74, no. 271: 130-131., (1983) (Box 17)
    - Schmitt. Review of Aristotle and the Renaissance., 1983 (Box 17)